# **Tom Hibbers**

# SOFTWARE ENGINEER

(+27) 82-298-7183

tomhibbers@gmail.com

Cape Town, ZA

tomhibbers.com

# **SUMMARY**

I have a passion for technology and business. I enjoy solving problems and leveraging new technologies. I am an engineer that can quickly learn and master new technologies. I have experience with a diverse range of technologies and languages, and currently specialize in full stack web development.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

**LexisNexis**, South Africa— Senior Software Engineer Sep 2020 - PRESENT

- Work on conveyancing software for Nedbank home loans department.
- Integrate with internal and external services such as Debicheck, document management, printing, reporting, etc all with different specifications, e.g. SOAP, REST, FTP
- Rewrite the existing legacy Windows Forms application in Angular.
- Swagger REST integration with legacy WCF services
- NSwag to streamline API integration between front and backend
- Web authentication for both AD and JWT
- Rewrite and redesign legacy UI for web

**RapidDeploy,** South Africa— Senior Software Engineer May 2020 - Aug 2020

- Utilize signalR to provide data to mobile CAD (Cloud Aided Dispatch) clients real-time in large distributed system
- Utilize event sourcing and CQRS to scale microservices

**Entelect,** South Africa— Intermediate Software Engineer May 2018 - May 2020

Allan Gray (Client):

- Developed Metric tool for software projects using Angular and React.
- TDD with Jenkins and Bitbucket Pipelines CI/CD.

## FNB (Client):

- Update Forex finance system frontend and backend using Java EE in a Linux environment.
- Develop Dockerized SOAP, REST and Message Services with Kubernetes.
- Add virtualization and provisioning to assist with the roll out across new regions.

## **EDUCATION**

Nelson Mandela Metropolitan University

BCom Hons, Computer Science and Information Systems 2012

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

ANGULAR	****
.NET	****
JAVA	***
DOCKER	****
KUBERNETES	***

# **SOFT SKILLS**

Leadership	****
Team Oriented	****
Creativity	****
Problem Solving	****
Communication	****

## Gumtree (Client):

- Work on Gumtree B2B system built on ASP.Net MVC 4.5.
- Rewrite legacy system to support DI
- Cloud Logging on Kibana instead of local disk logs
- Introduce testing using Moq and apply TDD to all new components
- Redesign DB to use repository pattern and separation of read and write models
- Migrate codebase from SVN to Git
- Introduce Octopus Deploy to CI/CD pipeline
- Rework .Net Framework components into .Net Core microservices

**Tigers Limited,** South Africa— Junior Software Developer Apr 2016 - Apr 2018

### Website:

 Develop an angular website to give customers visibility to their orders real-time across the supply chain. This included factories, warehouses, shipping and delivery.

## Backend Integrations:

- Develop new standardized API and reusable components to integrate with existing logistics and freight forwarding systems.
   Needed to be efficient and scalable as take-on of new clients was exponentially increasing and the infrastructure had yet to be moved to the cloud with dynamic provisioning.
- Work with low latency real-time data feeds in warehouses across multiple countries.
- Training of new developers and operational personnel.
- Create middleware to integrate X12 EDI and in-house standardized
  API to automate fulfillment for large retailers like Walmart.

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate: Web Applications (Apr 2017)
- Microsoft Certified Solutions Developer: App Builder (Jun 2017)

# **LANGUAGES**

English Fluent

Afrikaans Fluent